SARAH STROHKORB SEBO

sarah.sebo@yale.edu \(\) http://sarahsebo.com Department of Computer Science \(\) Yale University 51 Prospect Street, New Haven, CT, 06511, USA

RESEARCH OVERVIEW

My research focuses on the development of robot teammates that promote positive team social dynamics in addition to the reliable completion of assigned tasks. My work explores behaviors and mathematical frameworks social robots can use to shape group trust, assist in mental model sharing, and improve team performance.

Key words: Human-robot interaction (HRI), robotics, trust, social collaboration, groups and teams

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science

2014 - current

Yale University, Advisor: Brian Scassellati

B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

2010 - 2014

Franklin W. Olin College of Engineering

PUBLICATIONS

Peer-Reviewed Conference Papers

C4 Sarah Strohkorb Sebo, Margaret Traeger, Malte Jung, Brian Scassellati (2018). The Ripple Effects of Vulnerability: The Effects of a Robots Vulnerable Behavior on Trust in Human-Robot Teams. In Proceedings of the Thirteenth ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human Robot Interation (HRI 2018).

Acceptance rate: 23%

- C3 Nicole Salomons, Michael Van der Linden, **Sarah Strohkorb Sebo**, Brian Scassellati (2018). Humans Conform to Robots: Disambiguating Trust, Truth, and Conformity. In *Proceedings of the Thirteenth ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human Robot Interation (HRI 2018)*. Acceptance rate: 23%
- C2 Sarah Strohkorb, Ethan Fukuto, Natalie Warren, Charles Taylor, Bobby Berry, Brian Scassellati (2016). Improving Human-Human Collaboration Between Children With a Social Robot. In Proceedings of the 25th IEEE International Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (RO-MAN 2016).

Acceptance rate: 47%

C1 Sarah Strohkorb, Iolanda Leite, Natalie Warren, Brian Scassellati (2015). Classification of Childrens Social Dominance in Group Interactions with Robots. In *Proceedings of the 2015 ACM on International Conference on Multimodal Interaction (ICMI 2015)*.

Acceptance rate: 41%

Peer-Reviewed Workshop Papers

- Sarah Strohkorb and Brian Scassellati (2017). Cultivating Psychological Safety in Human-Robot Teams with Social Robots. In Proceedings of the 2017 Workshop on Robots in Groups and Teams at the 20th ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Collaborative Work and Social Computing.
- Sarah Strohkorb, Chien-Ming Huang, Aditi Ramachandran, Brian Scassellati (2016). Establishing Sustained, Supportive Human-Robot Relationships: Building Blocks and Open Challenges. In Proceedings of the 2016 AAAI Spring Symposium on Enabling Computing Research in Socially Intelligent Human-Robot Interaction: A Community-Driven Modular Research Platform. AAAI Press.
- Sarah Strohkorb, Brian Scassellati. Promoting Collaboration with Social Robots. In Proceedings of the Eleventh ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human Robot Interation (HRI 2016).
- Sarah Strohkorb, Brian Scassellati (2015). Promoting Social Collaboration between Children with a Social Robot. In Proceedings of the 2015 AAAI Fall Symposium on AI for Human-Robot Interaction (AI-HRI 2015). AAAI Press.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Intelligent Robotics, Yale University Teaching Assistant	Fall 2016, Spring 2017, Spring 2018, Fall 2018
CS50, Yale University Teaching Assistant	Fall 2015
Software Design, Olin College Teaching Assistant	Spring 2014

RANTS	
The 2017 HRI Pioneers Workshop at the 2017 ACM/IEEE International	2017
Conference on Human-Robot Interaction	
Key personnel, contributed to grant development and writing	
National Science Foundation	
PI: Brian Scassellati	
Travel Grants	
HRI Pioneers - General Chair Organizer	2016
Yale Computer Science Department grant to attend Grace Hopper Celebration	2016
HRI Pioneers - Attendee	2015
HRI Student Volunteer	2015
CRA-W Grad Cohort Workshop	2015
IENTORING	

\mathbf{N}

MENTORING		
Co-authored publication numbers refer to the publication lists above.		
Michael Schutzman, High School Student	2018	
Nicholas Chang, Yale Undergraduate	2018	
Ling Dong, Yale Undergraduate	2018	
Marc Harary, Yale Undergraduate	2018	

Priyanka Krishnamurthi, Yale Undergraduate	2017
Neil Madhavani, High School Student	2017
Rachel Ha, Yale Undergraduate	2017
Adam Erickson, Yale Undergraduate	2016
Isabelle Gallagher, High School Student	2016
Ethan Fukuto, Pomona College Undergraduate Publications: C2	2015
Bobby Berry, Yale Undergraduate Publications: C2	2015
Charles Taylor, Yale Undergraduate Publications: C2	2015
Natalie Warren, Yale Undergraduate Publications: C1, C2	2014 - 2015
SERVICE	
Organizing Committee	
HRI Pioneers Workshop at HRI 2017 General Co-Chair	2016-2017
Conference Paper Referee	
International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI)	2017-2018
International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)	2017
International Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (R Interaction Design and Children (IDC) Conference	(Co-MAN) 2016-2018 2018
Journal Article Referee	
ACM Transactions on Human-Robot Interaction	2018
IEEE Transactions on Cognitive and Developmental Systems	2017
International Journal of Child-Computer Interaction International Journal of Social Robotics	2017 2016
SELECTED OUTREACH	
Yale Social Robotics Lab Open Houses, Yale University, New Haven CT Robotics demonstrations including Nao, Keepon, and Jibo at annual lab open hou the public, drawing approximately 100 people each time the event was held from New Haven community.	
Teen Science Club Presentation, Guilford Library, Guilford CT	2016
Presented information and a robotics demonstration to a group of local teens interobotics.	rested in

PRESS